<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on DataSkool Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on DataSkool Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Python with Power BI</title>
      <link>/post/integrating-python-with-powerbi-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/integrating-python-with-powerbi-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has recently added Python support to Power BI Desktop. This is available as a preview feature for Power BI Desktop, yet a nice feature for those who use Python on a day to day basis. Python is an open source general purpose language and has become one of top programming languages for data science. Power BI is Microsoft’s flagship BI tool for creating dashboards and interactive reports.
Similar to R, with Python as a backend engine for Power BI Desktop, you can do many cool things, which can be categorized into three broad applications–</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power BI single R script for multiple data sets / tables</title>
      <link>/post/power-bi-single-r-script-for-multiple-data-sets-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/power-bi-single-r-script-for-multiple-data-sets-tables/</guid>
      <description>Power BI is a great tool for creating interactive statistical tables with the aid of R. When using R as a data connector, you can use a single R script to have multiple data frames loaded into Power BI.
Often, as we are developing the report, you will add or remove tables in the single R script. It is convenient to have all the codes in a single table since most of the data frames are derived from the main data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating R with Power BI</title>
      <link>/post/integrating-r-with-powerbi-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/integrating-r-with-powerbi-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Power BI Desktop version nicely integrates with R. R is an open source software for statistical computing and graphics. R has become popular among the data scientists because of its powerful data analytics and visualization capabilities. Power BI is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s flagship BI tool for creating dashboards and interactive reports. With R as a backend engine for Power BI Desktop, you can do many cool things, which can be categorized into three broad applications&amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>