<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on dataskool blog</title>
    <link>/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on dataskool blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>প‍্যাশন, প্রফেশনালিজম, ও প্রায়োরিটি</title>
      <link>/post/passion-professionalism-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/passion-professionalism-priority/</guid>
      <description>ভূমিকা কর্মক্ষেত্রে পরিসংখ‍্যানবিদদের ভূমিকা আমেরিকা সহ উন্নত দেশগুলিতে পরিসংখ‍্যানবিদদের তাদের কাজের কারণে বেশ গুরুত্ব দেয়া হয়। অর্থাৎ এসব দেশে পরিসংখ্যানবিদদের প্রফেশনাল ভ্যালু আছে। ব‍্যাপারটা বাংলাদেশের প্রেক্ষাপটে চিন্তা করলে বোঝা সহজ নয়।
উদাহরণ দিলে বুঝতে সহজ হবে।
বাংলাদেশে অনেক চাকুরীতে পরিসংখ‍্যানবিদ একটি যোগ্যতা হিসেবে চাওয়া হয়। কিন্তু সেখানে পরিসংখ‍্যানের কী ধরনের কাজ থাকে বা এই ব‍্যাকগ্রাউন্ডের কেউ যখন সেই চাকুরীতে প্রবেশ করে তখন তিনি অর্জিত জ্ঞানের কতটা ব‍্যবহার করতে পারেন সে সম্পর্কে আমার যা ধারণা হয়েছে তা থেকে বলা যায় অল্পকিছু ব‍্যাতিরেকে কর্মক্ষেত্রে পরিসংখ‍্যানবিদ হিসেবে পরিসংখ‍্যানের ছাত্র/ছাত্রীদের অংশগ্রহণ অনেকটা সীমিত।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statisticians in the Data Science Era</title>
      <link>/post/statisticians-in-the-data-science-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statisticians-in-the-data-science-era/</guid>
      <description>If you are exploring the hot field of Data Science today, you probably know by now that there is no unique way to define data science. Everyone’s perspective comes from their respective backgrounds. Statisticians think they are data scientists while CS folks think they are.
I would not go into the debate.
Both have truth in their arguments as the typical problems they solve are quite different. There are some exceptions where their workflows overlap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for statistics jobs in the industry</title>
      <link>/post/preparing-for-statistics-jobs-in-the-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/preparing-for-statistics-jobs-in-the-industry/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share a few things with you from recent experience of my transition from academia to industry. Of course I have a lot more experience than a fresh graduate, but something I’ve experienced that many others may benefit from. I believe this will help you to think at least. I’ve written this with the candidates in the US job market in mind.
Firstly, I would say this– lies, damn lies, statistics, AND one-page resume.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>